Washington and Lee University and Regional Virginia History Research Collection WLU.Coll.0668
Washington and Lee University, University Library Special Collections and Archives
Washington and Lee University and Regional Virginia History Research Collection
1609-2016
Washington and Lee University, University Library Special Collections and Archives
WLU.Coll.0668
12 Linear Feet
Box 1
Box 1-21
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research use.
- Academics: Economics, 1994-04-25; Gunn, John McKenzie, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Published lecture by retired professor John McKenzie Gunn, dated April 25, 1994; "Can Economics be Both Relevant and 'good'?"
- African Americans (Box 1, Folder 2-7)
  - African Americans, 1 Files (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Folder includes four items: "A Community's Stories" article from The News Gazzette concerning an exhibit by the Rockbridge Historical Society; a list of 'Old Lexington Colored People,' from the early 1900's from Leslie Lyle Campbell's notes; information on a group of slaves from Caroline County (a page copied from Colonial Caroline: a History of Caroline County, Virginia); and a letter to Special Collections concerning information on the holdings of records concerning black history in Virginia. Nine Historic Lexington Foundation interviews done for Black History Month 2016, mostly by Beverly Tucker, one by Anne McClung, and one by W&L Students Caitlin Mullen '05 and Anne Young '04, with Lexington African Americans and one Buena Vista resident.
    African Americans; Free blacks; Virginia -- Lexington; Virginia -- Buena Vista; Rockbridge Historical Society; Adamson, Emily B.; Cauthern, Leslie; Delaney, Theodore C., Jr., Dr.; Jones, Falvorees, Jr.; Morrison, Edlow; Scott, Margaret; Thompson, Irma Blake
    - Black In Lexington: Endurance and Hope in a Vanishing Community. education, business, religion, profiles, etc., 2010; 1 Item (Box 1, Folder 2)
      General
      Washington and Lee Student Journalism Project, by students Catherine Carlock, Erin Galliher, Farrell Ulrich, and Mike White.
      Morrison, Edlow; Collins, Courtney; Thompson, Irene; First Baptist Church (Lexington, Va.); Randolph Street Methodist Church (Lexington, Va.); Lylburn Downing School (Lexington, Va.); African-Americans. Lexington, Virginia; Baker, Wendell; Sloan, Alice; Merchant, Shawheim; Lackey, Tracey Dickerson; Dickerson-Suggs, Stacey
    - Black History Month 2016 in Lexington, Virginia. A Series of Interviews with Prominent Members of the African American Community, sponsored by the Historic Lexington Foundation., 9 Item (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Adamson, Emily B.; Cauthern, Leslie; Jones, Falvorees, Jr.; Scott, Margaret; Thompson, Irma Blake; Morrison, Edlow; Sloan, Alice; Delaney, Theodore C., Jr., Dr.
    - A Community's Stories: Vistors Wander Through Past At Opening of African-American Heritage Exhibit. The News-Gazette., 2001-02-28; 1 Item (Box 1, Folder 2)
      African-Americans. Lexington, Virginia
    - Black cemetery doubt remains: Were the bodies ever buried at Evergreen in Lexington, Virginia?, Washington Post., 2007-09-29; 3 Item (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Also includes Historical research of Lexington's Lost Cemetery.
    - Program, A Celebration of Life for Mother Frances Price Ragsdale, 1906-2011., 2011-03-8; 1 Item (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Ragsdale, Frances P.; African-Americans. Lexington, Virginia
    - Lexington's African American School, Randolph Street, papers., 6 Item (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - African Americans (Box 1, Folder 3)
    143 pages printed from the 1810 Virginia Census, listing "Other Free" Heads of Household, by family name.
  - Freed Slaves in Rockbridge Co., 1805-02-05-1860-05-07; 3 Item (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Register of Free Negroes of Rockbridge County, Virginia, with index. According to the Act of the General Assembly of Virginia. Passed January 25, 1803
    African Americans. Rockbridge County, Virginia
  - Register of Marriages, 1822-1866; 1 Item (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Photocopy
    Register of Marriages, Colored Persons in Rockbridge County under act of Virginia Assembly Passed February 27, 1866
  - Slavery, 1850-1991; Washington Post Company (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Copy of Washington Post article, "The Captive Nations of Slaves," covering an exhibit at the Museum of the Confederacy named "Before Freedom Came," 1991. Receipt for purchase of slave, John. January 26, 1850.
    Slavery; Dorsey, Phillip
  - Staunton, Virginia, 2016; 1 Item (Box 1, Folder 7)
    African-Americans. Staunton, Virginia
- Agriculture (Box 1, Folder 8-10)
  Agriculture
  - Agricultural Society of Rockbridge, 1839-10-17; 1 Item 4 pages Photocopy (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Address delivered before the Agricultural Society of Rockbridge, at its annual Fair, at Fancy Hill, October 17, 1839, by the Rev. Henry Ruffner, D. D., President of Washington College. The Lexington Gazette, and Rockbridge Farmer, June 23, 1840.
    Ruffner, Henry, Reverend; Agricultural Society of Rockbridge; Agriculture
  - Rockbridge Farmers Exchange to Hold Open House for Farmers in This Area as Part of John Deere Centennial Celebration, 1937; Rockbridge Farmers Exchange (Box 1, Folder 8)
    John Deere Centennial
  - Almanacs, 1874; Pierce, R.V. (Ray Vaughn), 1840-1914 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Folder includes "Pierce's Memorandum and Account Book: Designed for Farmers, Mechanics, and all People," 1872.
  - Livestock, 1892-1903 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Photocopy of ledger, 1892-1903.
    Livestock; Virginia -- Rockbridge County; Agriculture
- Alone Mill (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Folder includes a copy of a report of "Approval of Site, Plans, etc." for a school house at Alone Mill; a balance sheet by Alone Canning Co., and a photocopy of a pencil drawn map of Alone Mill.
  Alone Mill; Virginia -- Kerr's Creek; Virginia -- Rockbridge County
- Archaelogy, 1989; Russ, Kurt; McDaniel, John M., III (John Milton) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Folder includes "Selected Bibliography for Historic Artifact Identification and Analysis" prepared by Kurt C. Russ and John M. McDaniel, for distribution at 1989 ASV Historic Artifact Workshop.
  Archaeology -- Classification; Archaeology -- Classification -- Data processing
- Arnold's Valley (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Asheville, North Carolina, McCoy, George W. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Contains booklet titled "Battle of Asheville."
- Associations (Box 1, Folder 15-20)
  - APVA, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Contains two copies of "The Ruth Anderson McCulloch Branch of The Association for the Preservation of Virginia Antiguqities: 1896-1987."
    Association for the Preservation of Virginia Antiquities
  - Helpline, 1992-12; United Way of America (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Contains a booklet titled "A Rockbridge Area Resource Guide for People in Need." Prepared by Helpline/Information and Referral and United Way of Lexington-Rockbridge County.
    Virginia -- Lexington; Virginia -- Rockbridge County; Helplines; Social service
  - Lee Memorial, 1883; 1999; Barnes, Emily (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Contains student paper authored by Emily Barnes '01 titled "Lee Memorial Association." In addition, a copy of a sketch from 1883 about the Lee Memorial Association titled "Southern Historical Society Papers."
    Lee, Robert E., General (Robert Edward); Lee Memorial Association
  - Lexington Fire Department (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Lexington Fire Department (Lexington, Va.)
  - Rockbridge County Cooperative Extension, 1992; Virginia Cooperative Extension (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Booklet titled "Education for a Better Tomorrow, 1992 Annual Report."
    Virginia -- Rockbridge County; Rockbridge County Cooperative Extension
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 1996-04-1996-05 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    "Procedings" publication published by the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, including reports and activities of the 100th Annual Meeting in Atlanta Georgia as well as current lists of member insitutions.
  - HorseMania brochure, a local public art project benefiting Blue Ridge Court Appointed Special Advocates for Children (Box 1, Folder 20)
    HorseMania is a local public art project whose 13 life-sized fiberglass horses were fabricated by local artisan, Mark Cline, painted by local artists, sponsored by businesses and individuals, and placed throughout the cities of Lexington and Buena Vista as well as Rockbridge County, with the purpose of raising funds for Blue Ride CASA for Children.
    Court Appointed Special Advocates (CASA) is a non-profit organization serving our area's most severely abused, abandoned and neglected children through the recruitment, training, and supervision of community volunteers who advocate for their best interests.
    Blue Ridge CASA for Children
- Augusta County, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
  Virginia -- Augusta County
  - History, 1758; Henning, William Waller (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Includes photocopy of a 1758 schedule titled "To the Militia of the Coutny of Augusta, and for Provisions furnished by sundry inhabitants of the said county, viz."
    Virginia -- Augusta County; Regional planning -- Laws, statutes, etc. -- U.S. states
  - Militia (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Battle of Cowpens (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Biography, 1700-2018 (Box 2, Box 2-10)
  - Addison, John West, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    File includes photocopies of two letters concerning Washington and Lee student, John West Addison.
    Educators -- Biography
  - Ailstock, Private, 1894; Paxton, Alex. S. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Article titled "A Confederate Hero," from Blue and Gray, 1984.
    United States -- Confederate States of America; Ailstock, Private
  - Alexander, Archibald, 1997; Taylor, Alex (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Biography compiled in 1997 concerning Archibald Alexander (5 pgs. long).
    Alexander, Archibald
  - Alexander, Hortense, 1999; 1893 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Correspondence about the Washington and Lee Homecoming Queen from c.1893 and her protrait which hangs in the Special Collections vault (WLU Coll PP 0081).
    Homecoming; Alexander, Hortense
  - Allen, Donald (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Allan, William, 1889-2007; Washington and Lee University. Trustees; Tucker, John Randolph (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Contains an article titled "Colonel William Allan at McDonough"; an 1889 address by J. Randolph Tucker; and an 1890 memorial by Washington and Lee Board of Trustees concerning Allan.
    Allan, William, 1837-1889
  - Allen, James M., 1898-04 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Includes a biography and illustration of Allen under the title of "The Headlight."
    Kentucky -- Cynthiana
  - Anderson, Jo., 1970; Reasons, George (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Photocopry of newpaper article concerning Anderson, slave of Cyrus McCormick.
    Anderson, Jo; McCormick, Cyrus Hall, 1809-1884
  - Anderson, Mary P. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Anderson, Mary P., - 1885
  - Armstrong, George Dod, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Photocopy of biography concerning Armstrong from the "Dictionary of American Biography."
    Armstrong, George D.
  - Armstrong, Rick, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Article titled "Civil War Author on the Trail of History."
    Armstrong, Rick
  - Auden, Constance Rosalie, Auden, W.H. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Two copies of a Christmas oration in memoriam of Constance Rosalie Auden.
    Auden, Constance Rosalie, 1870-1941
  - Baker, John (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Ballengee, James, 2002; The Roanoke Times (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Obituaries, clipped from Roanoke Times 2002.
    Ballangee, James
  - Barclay, Alexander Tedford, 1997; Taylor, Alex (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Biography of Alexander Tedford Barclay compiled by Washington and Lee student in 1997.
    Barclay, Ted, II (Alexander Tedford); Barclay family
  - Barclay, William Houston, 1997; Taylor, Alex (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Biography compiled in 1997 and geneological chart showing many prominent people of Rockbridge County.
    Barclay, William Houston; Barclay family
  - Barclay Family, 1997; Taylor, Alex (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Narrative titled "Aunt Elizabeth Remembers;" interview with retired Washington and Lee professor, Charles Turner.
    Barclay, Elizabeth; Telford, Jane Edmondson; Barclay, Polly Culbertson; Paxton, Phebe Alexander; Moore, Andrew; Turner, Charles W. (Charles Wilson)
  - Barkley, Alben, 1956-1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Photocopies of newspaper clippings concerning the death of Barkley at Washington and Lee University.
    Barkley, Alben William
  - Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1805; Johnson, Edward (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Photocopy of a letter to George Baxter from Edward Johnson introducing Dr. Barton, December 21, 1805. Pamphlet entitled, "How Many Botany Books Did Thomas Jefferson Own?" mentioning Dr. Barton.
    Botany; Book collecting; Baxter, George Addison; Barton, Benjamin Smith, Dr., 1766-1815; Jefferson, Thomas
  - Basse, Edgar Alfred Jr., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Photocopy of Calyx 1939 yearbook picture. Basse gave donation towards Special Collections workroom.
    Basse, Edgar Alfred, Jr.
  - Beggs, Alexander (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Blackburn, Thomas, 1854; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    "Fatal Affray," Lexington Gazette, January 19, 1854. Murder of Cadet Thomas Blackburn.
    Murder -- Investigation; Virginia -- Lexington; Blackburn, Thomas
  - Blakemore, Benjamin (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Boatwright Family (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Photocopies of Calyx yearbook pictures and Alumni directory information. John G. Boatwright '15 made donation for the University Library reading room in memory of Robert McDearmon Boatwright '42.
    Boatwright, Robert McDearmon; Boatwright, John G.; Boatwright Family
  - Bodie, Charles (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Brewbaker, Pete (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Booth, Lea, 2006-05-12; Washington and Lee University. News Office (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Obituary, Washington and Lee University News Home, 5/12/2006.
    Booth, Augustus Lea
  - Borden, Benjamin, Sr. and Jr., 1997; Taylor, Alex (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Two separate biographies for Borden Jr. and Sr.
    Borden, Benjamin, Sr.
  - Brady, Pat, 2001; The Roanoke Times; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.) (Box 2, Folder 29)
    E-mail message to the Washington and Lee community concerning Brady's death, obituaries from the News-Gazette and The Roanoke Time. Article titled "'Pat' Brady's Life One of Quiet Service to a Community He Loved So Dearly," the News-Gazette.
    Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
  - Brcin, John David, 1967; Hoffmann, August Carl (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Brcin, John David
  - Brooks Family, 1861; Brooks, William; White, James J. (James Jones); Brooks family; Brooks, Andrew (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Photocopy of letter from Andrew Brooks to sister, January 23,1861; photocopy and written transcript of letter from James J. White relating to the death of William Brooks, July 16,1861; photocopy of telegram to J.M. Brooks relating to the remains of his son, William Brooks, July 20,1861; Diary entries written by Andrew Brooks in Augusta County.
    Brooks, James M.; Confederate States of America. Army. Liberty Hall Volunteers; Confederate States of America. Army. Stonewall Brigade; Confederate States of America. Army. Virginia Infantry Regiment, 4th
  - Brouwer, Margaret, 1995-1996; Roanoke Symphony Orchestra; Roanoke Valley Choral Society (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Composer in Residence, Roanoke Symphony Orchestra, Roanoke Valley Choral Society, 1995-1996, pgs. 7-8.
    Brouwer, Margaret Lee
  - Brown, Alexander S., 1846-1849 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Photocopies of letters to his sister, Fannie, September 20, 1846, and September 7, 1848, while a student at Washington College. Original letters reside at Virginia Military Academy Archives.
    Brown, Fannie
  - Brown, Clarence J. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Radio script concerning Clarence Brown used in Cincinnati, Ohio on the radio program, "Personalities in your Government."
    Radio scripts; Ohio -- Cincinnati
  - Brown Family, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Robert and Benjamin Brown's relatives who attended Washington and Lee University. A letter addressed to President John Delane Wilson from their mother, Elizabeth Barry Brown.
    Wilson, John Delane; Brown, Robert; Brown, Benjamin
  - Brown, John, 1930-1959 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    Folder includes a Civil War centennial commemorative edition of the Valley News Echo concerning John Brown's Raid and Harper's Ferry(2 copies); Stanton Spectator article titled "The Out-break at Harper's Ferry"; Stanton Spectator article concerning John Brown's execution titled "Results of the Trial"; Richmond Times-Dispatch article titled "Documents in Treason Trial of John Brown; The Sunday Baltimore article titled "Verdict Missing in Brown Papers; a history course examinaton concerning this time period; an account by someone named "Jackson" of John Brown's execution addressed to his wife.
    West Virginia -- Harpers Ferry; John Brown's Raid (Harpers Ferry, West Virginia: 1859); Brown, John
  - Brown, Manly, 1998-2001; The Roanoke Times; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.) (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Articles from three local newspapers titled "He's a Third-Generation Blacksmith," "The Village Blacksmith, Manly Brown, Dies at 93," "Family Dreams of Living Museum. Jack Chaffee as Blacksmith and Curator of Brown's Forge."
    Brown, Manley
  - Brown, Samuel (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Brown, William (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Includes photocopy of the Ministerial Directory of the Presbyterian Church in the United States highlighting William Brown.
    Patterson, William Brown
  - Bruinsma, Theodore, 1999; Los Angeles Times (Firm) (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Contains obituary of Bruinsma dated September 17, 1999.
    Bruinsma, Theodore
  - Buchanan, William (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Buchanan, William
  - Buchser, Frank (Box 2, Folder 42)
    File includes color notecard of Frank Buchser painting of Robert E. Lee, "The Last Life Portrait of General Robert E. Lee," a letter from Buchser to Lee concerning a portrait, Washington and Lee News Release titled "General Lee 'Comes Home' for His Birthday," Religious Herald article titled "Valentine's Recumbent Statue of General Robert E. Lee," and correspondence between various researchers interested in this topic and Special Collections.
    Buchser, Frank; Lee, Robert E., General (Robert Edward)
  - Buncombe, Edward (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Booklet titled "Edward Buncombe and Buncombe County."
    North Carolina -- Buncombe County; Buncombe, Edward
  - Campbell, Ben, 1921; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Obituary, "Thrown from Horse...," by Lexington Gazette.
    Campbell, Ben Miller
  - Campbell, Edmund D., 1995-12-13; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Obituary found in the News-Gazette about Edmund Campbell, a Washington and Lee graduate and attorney who worked on various cases concerning desegregation of Virginia schools.
    Civil rights; De facto school segregation; Campbell, Edmund Douglas
  - Campbell, Henry Donald, 1934-1935; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    File includes a biography excerpt from "Who's Who in America" and an obituary by the Lexington Gazette.
    Campbell, Henry Donald
  - Campbell, John L., 1867-1886; Campbell, Robert Fishburne; Jackson, Thomas Jonathan (Stonewall) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    File includes an obituary of John Lyle Campbell Sr. by the Lexington Gazette, a biography writtten by his son Robert Fishburne Campbell, and copies of letters between Robert E. Lee and Prof. Campbell as well as T.J. Jackson and Prof. Campbell.
    Campbell, J. L. (John Lyle); Lee, Robert E., General (Robert Edward)
  - Canfield, Verne, 1995; The Roanoke Times; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.); Washington and Lee University, Department of Athletics, Basketball (Box 3, Folder 5)
    File includes article "Coach Nears End of Not-So-Typical Career: Washington and Lee's Canfield Prepares for Life After 31 Years of Generals' Basketball," and a Roanoke Times article named " 'I Hope I've Touched Some Lives.' "
    Canfield, Verne D.
  - Carrick, Samuel Czar (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Biography by the American National Biography Online.
    Carrick, Samuel Czar
  - Carroll, Robert Patrick, 1994-04-20; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Contains one photocopy of obituary by News-Gazette.
    Carroll, Robert Patrick
  - Cash, Woody, 1998; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Obituary by the News-Gazette.
  - Castle, Gray, 1999-05-29 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Memorial program for Gray Castle.
    Castle, Gray, 1931-1999
  - Caudill, Charles, 1994-02; The Roanoke Times (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Roanoke Times article concerning Caudill's retirement.
    Caudill, Charles, Col.
  - Cavendish, William Henderson, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Contains a booklet titled "The Cavendish Family History."
    Cavendish, William Henderson; Cavendish, Andrew
  - Chamberlain, George Earle, 1909-1911 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Folder includes biography and copies of two letters from Theofore Roosevelt, one concerning a memorial to Robert E. Lee and the other one concerning Chamberlain's son.
    Chamberlain, George E. (George Earle); Roosevelt, Theodore; Lee, Robert E., General (Robert Edward)
  - Chavis, John, Delaney, Theodore C., Jr., Dr. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Folder contains at least twenty eight separate items concerning John Chavis, from articles, portraits, letters, records, to research papers concerning his role in Washington and Lee Lee as well as African American history. Also included are the W&L Alumni magazine artices, "Chavis House named," March/April 1986 and "Chavis House dedicated," November/December 1986.
    African Americans; Chavis, John
  - Chenoweth, B.D. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Childress, Robert (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Chittum, Fanny Turner, 1894; Rockbridge County News (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Includes obituary by Rockbridge County News.
    Chittum, Fanny Turner, 1809-1894
  - Claytor, Alexander, B., 1995; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.) (Box 3, Folder 17)
    File contains obituary by the News-Gazette.
    Claytor, Alexander B., 1910-1995
  - Cline, Patsy, 1940; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.) (Box 3, Folder 18)
    File includes an article titled Honor Rolls," a set of photographs, and a pamphlet commemorating her life and work.
    Cline, Patsy
  - Cocke, Lucian H., 1927; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Folder includes an obituary written by The Lexington Gazette.
    Cocke, Lucian Howard
  - Cody, William F. "Buffalo Bill" (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Cooke, John Esten (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Cooke, John Esten
  - Crawford, Jane Todd (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Crenshaw, Marjorie Buford, 1994-01-12; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.) (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Lexington Gazette obituary about Crenshaw.
    Crenshaw, Marjorie Buford, 1912-1994
  - Crittenden, John Jordan, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    The file includes a biography by the American National Biography Online.
    Crittenden, John J. (John Jordan), 1787-1863
  - Custis, Daniel Parke, 1909-10; Virginia Historical Society (Box 3, Folder 25)
    File includes a photocopied catalogue of the Library of Daniel Parke Custis: From a Manuscript in the Collection of the Virginia Historical Society, "The Magazine of History and Biography," October 1909, pages 404-412.
    Custis, Daniel Parke
  - Custis, John Parke, 1927-10 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    The Library of John Parke Custis, Esq., of Fairfax County, Virginia, "Tyler's Quarterly," October 1927, pages 97-103.
    Virginia -- Fairfax County; Custis, John Parke
  - Dale, Rebecca, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    File includes a greeting card made by the Artists of the Lexington, Virginia Note Card Series, 2002.
    Dale, Rebecca
  - Daniels, Jonathan M., 2006-03-26 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    The file includes a program in memory of Daniels, hosted at Robert E. Lee Memorial Church.